FERNANDA Thiesen

Front end developer

CONTACT DETAILS

Email: fcthiesen@gmail.com

Phone: 647 818 7114
Portfolio: <u>ferncodes.com</u>
GitHub: <u>github.com/fthiesen</u>

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/fernanda-

<u>thiesen</u>

PERSONAL PROFILE

An independent self-starter front-end developer who uses her curious mind, attention to detail and persistence to innovate and solve problems in order to build intuitive and accessible websites and applications. With 20 years of experience in working as a graphic design and marketing freelancer, I bring the ability to critically evaluate information, make decisions, accept criticism and feedback, and work effectively with people. I am looking to explore new opportunities that help me grow as a developer.

SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML5, CSS, SCSS
- Responsive Design
- JavaScript (ES6+), jQuery and React
- Working with RESTful APIs and Firebase
- Website accessibility requirements
- Version control & collaboration using Git and GitHub
- Paired programming and teambased development
- Project scope management
- Decision maker
- Team player
- Innovator

PROJECTS

POPSIPOLL

HTML5, SCSS, Firebase, React

An app that allows anyone to create a polling room and share the link with the participants. The users can vote and see the results. https://popsipoll.netlify.app/

MUST WATCH

HTML5, SCSS, API, Firebase, React

A movie recommendation app built with React, Firebase and the OMDb API.

https://must-watch.netlify.app/

AMAZED BY TV

HTML5, SCSS, Javascript, API

A one-page website created with JavaScript that connects to the TV Maze API and displays information about a chosen TV show. https://amazedbytv.netlify.app/

EDUCATION

JUNO COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY (2020-2021)

Web Development Immersive Bootcamp Certificate JavaScript Fundamentals Intro to Web Development

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN SOCIAL COMMUNICATIONS AND MARKETING (2001)

FACHA - Faculdades Integradas Hélio Alonso, Brazil

TECHNICAL SCHOOL CERTIFICATE IN ADVERTISING (1997)

ETEC - Escola Técnica de Comunicação, Brazil

EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE WEB DESIGNER AND MARKETER (1999-2021)

Brazil, Canada

- Engaged with hundreds of small business owners and managers, uncovering their needs and suggesting marketing and graphic design ideas as well as WordPress functionalities and website solutions.
- Worked both individually and with hosting support teams to troubleshoot WordPress and server issues for clients.

SELF-EMPLOYED WEB DESIGNER, EDITOR-IN-CHIEF, MARKETER (2009-2021)

OiCanada Digital Magazine, Canada

- Developed the magazine from scratch and reached a substantial average of 100,000 page views per month in 2016, having published more than 1,500 pieces.
- Created several designs over the years, keeping up with innovative ideas, and customized WordPress themes to match the magazine's brand guidelines.
- Engaged with several advertisers, understanding their campaign goals to help them promote their businesses to the magazine's audience and generate leads through banner ads, paid content, landing pages, email marketing and social media marketing.